

Samy CHBINOU

DevOps Workflow Engineer

Imp Juan, ANTIBES, FR

06 67 89 55 87

samy.chbinou@esna.cloud

https://chbinousamy.github.io/resume/resume.pdf

English, Italian, French

BACKGROUND

ABOUT

51 years old, Telecom & Software engineering education, I worked in software industry on real time embedded applications for mobile phones, IP multimedia set top boxes. Moreover, lately, I worked in setup Cloud Native infrastructure platforms for software development toolchains, (today called DevOps) for Build and CI/CD Worflows and Data processing in Docker containerization.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Career Break, Relocation, Antibes 06

Oct. 2021 - Present

DevOps, NAVYA, La Défense 92

Sep, 2021 - Oct, 2021 1 month

NAVYA Drive delivers autonomous driving. In a Agile team of 5 persons I added Gitlab pipelines automation for Continuous Integration Tests. I also setup some Gitlab runners to handle load CI tests. Directly installed on Bare Metal and on some VMs, Virtualbox and AWS

CI pipelines on Gitlab self hosted runners

Docker Buildx Python Containers

Artificial Intelligence Engineer, VALEO, Créteil 94

May, 2021 - Jul, 2021 1 month

Valeo, In the transversal GEEDS entity, I assist in relocation of the R&D Datacenter from Paris to Créteil.

- o Buildx Nvidia python Docker Containers
- Assistance in relocating a Datacenter from Paris to Creteil

Platform Engineer, Nokia Bell Labs, Nozay 78

Oct, 2014 - Dec, 2020 6 years 2 months

Nokia Bell Labs, Cloud RAN Entity, Cloud for Radio Access Networks which interconnects UE radio devices such as Phones, IoT, Automotive, Virtual Reality User Equipments. I worked as freelance in a 'StartUp Garage'. I setup a On-Prems, PaaS context to make some tests on different types of Cloud Native 5G technologies: storage databases, ethernet over fiber, docker containers and kubernetes clusters, Machine Learning DevOps pipelines

- Wrote Statement Of Work définitions with scope of work, project objectives, task schedules and deliverables
- Benchmarking CPU Offloading on Nvidia GPU, Xilinx FPGA, Ethernet over Optical Fiber (RDMA)
- Java Kafka pipelines & NodeJS Express websockets
- N-Tiers Microservices Architectures: Docker, NoSQL Databases, Kubernetes, Cloud Native Serverless
- Machine learning and Neural Networks Data engineering

Career Break,

Apr, 2013 - Oct, 2014 1 year 5 months

Software Test Engineer, Ercom Mobipass®, Vélizy 78

Dec, 2006 - Apr, 2013 6 years 3 months

Ercom, Mobipass®, I developed the Mobipass® project with a 5-100 person Télécom team to make it a recognized working software product. Mobipass® is a lab-based emulation product capable of precise reproduction of the behaviors of thousands of devices with mixed traffic calls and RF conditions experienced on a real network. Its easy-to-use GUI, advanced multi-UE channel emulator, integrated QoS and QoE test features and rich KPI capabilities make it a strong test and measurement addition for mobile network operators deploying advanced broadband networks. As Software engineer, I developed the GUI, User Interface in .NET C# language and did many tests on the TCP/IP Network.

- o Processing Network Datagram Blocks: Cut & Reassemble, Encode & Decode
- Object Oriented Programing to Design and Develop the UI in C#.NET
- Night Builds, Continuous Integration and Validation Tests

SKILLS





Scripting Languages



Github CI/CD Ad	Ctions	ab CI/CD Pipelines	Build Artifacts	Docker Containers	Kubernetes Pods
Helm					
Processors Arch	nitecture				
Linux ARM & Int	tel MacOS	M1 & Intel			
EDUCATION					
Digital Communica	ation System	ns & Technology, M	1Sc. Engineer , CH	ALMERS - Göteborg,	SWEDEN
Digital Communica	ation System	ns & Technology, M	1Sc. Engineer, CH	ALMERS - Göteborg,	SWEDEN
Digital Communica Sep, 1996 - Sep, 1997 Telecom and Softw			_	_	SWEDEN
			_	_	SWEDEN
Digital Communica Sep, 1996 - Sep, 1997 Telecom and Softw Sep, 1994 - Jun, 1996			_	_	SWEDEN